For those who have not read the plaque,
we will read the plaque.
Here men from the planet Earth
first set foot upon the moon
July 1969.
We came in peace for all mankind.
If this isn't an insanely beautiful woman,
I am hanging up.
Sir.
I-I-I think you should listen to this.
Sir?
Goddamn it!
Damn!
Sir?
Damn.
Come on baby. Come on baby.
Come on baby. Come on.
This better not be another
damn Russian spy job!
Boys from Air Traffic Res say
the skies are clear.
It's the real thing.
A radio signal from another world.
Let-Let's-Let's not jump the gun here.
Get online with Space Command.
They are gonna want to know about...
what's with the golf balls.
You are gonna kill me here.
Wait. Wait. This can't be right.
The calculated distance from source...
is only 375,000km.
It's coming from the moon.
Who else knows about this?
S.E.T.I. in New Mexico identified a signal.
But...
they are even more confused
than we are sir.
Excuse me.
Major!
Yes sir.
Radar reception has been impaired
but we were able to get these.
We estimate that it has a diameter
of over 550km,
and a mass roughly one
fourth the size of our moon.
What the hell is it?
A meteor?
No sir.
No, definitely not.
How do you know?
Well sir, it's slowing down.
It's what?
It's...
It's slowing down sir.
Get me the Secretary of Defense.
Then wake him!
Hello.
Hi. It's me.
Hi.
What time is it there?
It's 2:45 in the morning.
I know I didn't wake you.
As a matter of fact, you did.
Liar.
I have a confession to make.
I am sleeping...
next to a beautiful young brunette.
You didn't let her stay up
all night watching TV?
Did you?
Of course not.
You are gonna come home right
after the luncheon right?
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Mommy?
Here is your mother.
Hi honey!
Hi. I miss you.
I know, I miss you too.
President Whitmore's approval ratings
have slipped below 40%.
Even his crime bill failed to pass.
He is good.
Are the salad days over for
President Whitmore?
More talk.
Leadership as a pilot in the Gulf War
is completely different from
leadership in politics.
Daddy let me watch Letterman.
Traitor.
That's the problem.
They elected a warrior and they got a wimp.
Good morning George.
Good morning Mr. President.
That game could not have been pretty.
Thank you sir.
Connie you are up awfully early this morning.
They are not attacking your policies sir.
They are attacking your age.
Whitmore seems less like the president
and more like the orphan child Oliver asking.
Please sir I would like some more.
That's clever.
Yeah well I am not laughing.
Age was never an issue
when you stuck to your guns.
You were thought of as young idealistic.
Thanks.
Now...
the message has gotten lost.
It's just too much politics
too much compromise.
Isn't it amazing how quickly
everyone can turn against you?
It's a fine line between standing behind
a principle and...
hiding behind one.
You can tolerate a little compromise
if you are actually managing
to get something accomplished.
Well...
The Orange County Dispatch has voted you
one of the ten sexiest men...
of the year.
That's...
That's accomplishing something.
Excuse me Mr. President.
It's the Secretary of Defense.
Yes.
Could you say that again?
Station WXBY out here in Brooklyn.
The temperature is 95
degrees in Central Park.
What it is here in the borough
God only knows.
Let's go to Nick Jones.
He will give us a traffic
report to the beaches...
So what are you waiting?
My Social Security will expire
you will still be sitting there.
I am thinking.
Yeah well think already!
Have you any idea how long it takes
for those things to decompose?
If you don't move soon
I am gonna start to decompose.
Listen David, I have been meaning
to talk with you.
It's nice that you see me so much now but...
Don't.
Don't start Dad.
I am only saying it's been what?
Four years?
You are still wearing a wedding band?
Three years.
Alright three, four. You are divorced.
Come on. Move on.
This is not healthy.
No this is not healthy.
Smoking is not healthy.
Checkmate.
Wait a minute, wait a minute,
wait a minute.
Wait, wait, wait. This is not...
This is not checkmate.
See you tomorrow Pop.
No, no, no, just hold on.
This is not checkmate.
Checkmate.
Yes, we have got everybody we have
working on the problem.
I love XFiles too.
I hope you get to see it.
David! David!
What's the hell is the point of having a beeper
if you are not gonna turn it on?
It was turned on, I was ignoring you.
Hello. What's the...
What's the big emergency?
It started this morning.
Every station's making like it's the 1950s.
We got static. We got snow.
All kinds of distortions.
Nobody knows...
What are you doing? There is a reason
we have bins labeled recycle.
What the hell is going on?
My God in heaven.
So sue me. David!
We got a problem.
Did you try to switch transponder channels?
Oh please. You think I would be this
panicked if it was something simple?
Ok. Let's...
point the dish at another satellite.
We tried that. It didn't work.
It's almost as though
they were not even there.
Alright. What have we got here?
This is impossible.
We created a race of robots.
Their function...
Miguel the signal is all screwed up.
Stop it.
Just leave it alone.
You are gonna break it alright?
It's so fuzzy.
Oh no.
Good morning Lucas.
You see these?
I got a whole god damn crop,
full of these.
If your father is not in the air
in 20 minutes...
I am getting someone else.
Hey Russell!
Hey Miguel!
Russell!
What are you doing?
Just what in the hell
do you think you are doing?
It's the wrong field you idiot.
Lucas' farm is on the other side of town.
Are you sure?
CNS is running a story
that we are covering up
some type of nuclear testing experiment.
So tell them to run with it if they
want to embarrass themselves.
NASA's been on my butt all morning.
They want to know our position.
Our official position is
we have no official position.
Connie what is going on here?
Come on guys,
would I keep you out of the loop?
Yes absolutely.
In a second.
So what?
I can't hear you.
At the moment our satellites are
somewhat unreliable.
Isn't it possible that this thing
may just pass us by?
What if it doesn't pass us by?
Let's re-target some ICBMs
to blow it out of the sky.
And risk turning one dangerous
falling object into many?
We don't yet know enough
about what we are dealing with
to make any kind of intelligent judgments.
Luckily the press is making up
their own story at this point.
But that's not gonna keep.
We may need to upgrade to DEFCON 3.
Absolutely.
General contact NORAD.
You tell them we have upgraded
to DEFCON 3.
That's not what the President said.
Don't you think that's a little premature?
I don't think so.
We have over 50% of the armed forces
out on weekend leave.
Not to mention, the commanders and troops
that are in town for the 4th of July parade.
Go ahead Commander.
Our intelligence,
tells us the object
has settled into a stationary orbit.
Well, that's good news.
Not really sir.
Part of it has broken off into nearly
three dozen other pieces
smaller than the whole sir
yet over 15 miles in width themselves.
Where are they heading?
They should be entering our atmosphere
within the next 25 minutes.
Take us to DEFCON 3.
Please tell me we are getting somewhere.
Oh there is good news
and there is bad news.
Alright. What's the bad news?
The bad news is there is no
penalty for disturbing my lunch.
And the good news is
you are not gonna charge me.
No the good news,
is that I found the problem.
It's not our equipment.
It's some kind of weird signal
embedded in the satellite feed.
Wait that's the good news?
Yeah, because this signal
has a definite sequential pattern.
So as soon as I find
the exact binary sequence
then I can calculate the phase reversal with that
analyzer I bought for your birthday and apply it
we should be able to block it out completely.
And then we will be the only guys in town
with a clear picture!
Yes! Yes! Yes! Oh David!
That's why I love you!
That's not necessary.
Yes!
Too kind.
This better be good.
Captain on deck!
Sir we are looking at a total radar
blackout over a 13 km area.
Let's do a diagnostic check...
Excuse me sir.
The radar may be malfunctioning
but the infrared
is totally off the map.
Jeez.
Get me Atlantic Command on the line.
Hang on sir.
Sir, we have visual range
with incoming over Iraqi airspace.
Second sighting?
Yes sir.
This just came in from the Persian Gulf.
Correction sir.
We now have two confirmed
visual contacts.
That's affirmative. Mr. President.
They are tracking another one
off the California coastline.
Alright go ahead.
Put it on.
General you might want to watch this.
Yes sir.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Ladies and gentlemen
we are interrupting our regular broadcast
to bring you extraordinary events
taking place in the Russian Republic.
This unexplained disturbance
and the hysteria that it's
causing are incredible.
How would you describe
what you are seeing?
It is clearing the mountains
moving too slowly to be a comet
or meteor.
Widespread panic has gripped
the countryside
as thousands have taken to the streets.
It is confirmed.
The unexplained phenomenon
is headed for Moscow.
Mr. President we have
an AWAC off the West Coast.
ETA with contact point three minutes.
I don't understand it sir.
Side radar doesn't see it.
I know. It's blind sir.
Nothing is registering.
Negative.
We have zero visibility.
Visibility is at zero.
Command this is Eagle Eye 370.
Captain the president is listening.
Repeat what you just told me.
We still have zero visibility.
Instrumentation is malfunctioning.
We can't get any kind of reading
of what's in front of us.
Wait a minute.
Maybe clearing.
Pull up! Pull up!
Line is gone sir.
Two more have been spotted
over the Atlantic.
One is moving toward New York
the other's headed this direction.
How much time do we have?
Less than 10 minutes.
Alex organize a military escort.
Mr. President I strongly recommend
we move you to a secure
location immediately.
Connie can we expect the same
kind of panic we saw in Russia?
More than likely.
Mister President.
We can discuss this on the way.
I am not leaving.
We have to maintain
a working government...
I want you to get the vice president
the whole cabinet and joint chiefs
and take them to a secured location.
I am staying.
I don't want to add to a public hysteria
that's gonna cost lives.
Connie.
Yes sir.
We will initiate the Emergency
Broadcast System.
We will advise people, not to panic.
The best idea right now,
is to stay in their homes.
Yes sir.
Roy. Dean.
Alex you contact the cabinet members.
Have them rendezvous here.
We will take them to NORAD.
Mr. President with your permission
I would like to remain at your side.
I had a feeling you would.
And what happens if they do become hostile?
Then God help us.
There it is the strange
atmospheric phenomenon.
It is apparently what has been causing
all the distortions in our broadcasts.
David are you watching this?
Not to react in a manner of cold fear.
We have no evidence that these
phenomena are endangering anyone.
Thus far reports of aggression
Well, Marty li-li-listen to this.
I got a lock on the pattern of that
signal so we can filter it out but...
if my calculations are right it's going
to be gone in like seven hours anyway.
It's reducing itself every time it recycles
so eventually it's gonna disappear...
You listening?
Can you believe this.
David have not you been watching?
David!
General.
Good afternoon.
So far the phenomenon has
not caused any damage.
We have to ask you to try to stay calm
and it's important for everyone not to panic.
We have a fix on three
of the occurrences about to appear...
over American cities.
It's just unreal.
Hey Miguel come here.
One is headed towards Los Angeles.
The other two are on our eastern seaboard
headed towards New York,
and Washington D.C.
Marty. Marty.
Jamie says this building
has an old bomb shelter.
We are heading down there now.
Alright, alright everybody,
head down to the basement.
Take it slow.
Don't run.
Walk down to the basement.
There is no shame in hiding.
Oh I better call my mother.
Well look who we have here.
Hey Russ I heard you had a little trouble
this morning.
Dusted the wrong field.
Well I know you are probably still
a little confused
from your hostage experience.
Hostage experience.
Did something happen to you Russ?
Oh yeah.
Seems years back our boy
was kidnapped by aliens.
Did all kind...
of experiments on him and such.
Tell them about it Russ.
You get a couple of beers in him
and he will tell you all about it crazy stuff.
Won't you Russ?
Russ...
when they took you up in their spaceship
did they do any...
sexual things do you recall?
Do you recollect?
Oh Russ!
Let's get out of here.
What's going on? What's going on?
What's that?
Let's get out of here.
Come on.
Mommy! Look it!
It's too early baby.
Is it a earthquake?
Not even a four pointer.
Go back to sleep.
Daddy!
What are you doing here?
You should be down in the shelter.
What's going on?
Aren't you coming David?
No. I got to see this.
That's cool man!
You jerk!
The signal.
My God.
Now what do we do?
Address the nation.
There is gonna be a lot of
frightened people out there.
Yeah.
I am one of them.
Hey. Hey. Hey. Come on.
He is just trying to impress you.
If you want to impress me
you need to get a job,
and stop slobbering all over my shoe.
I don't believe this. Jasmine.
Neighbors moving out.
Guess they finally got tired
of all these quakes.
A little shake and they running.
Police and the fire departments are
asking everyone to stay off the phone.
Baby there is something on
the news about the quake.
The police are asking us not to call 911.
What's up man?
Hi daddy.
What you been doing out there?
Shooting the aliens.
Oh you shooting aliens right?
You think you tough?
What you got?
Turn around.
Let me see what you got.
Come on Boomer.
Let's get you something to eat.
Oh no...
Watch out. Watch it now baby.
I will go grab the paper.
Alright.
Dam...
Honey let's go!
Babe! you want some of this coffee?
Babe.
Pentagon officials are reporting
more ships,
have just arrived
over the capitals of India
England and Germany
bringing estimates up
to anywhere from 10,
to 15 of these city-sized spacecraft.
I know Ma. Just try and stay calm.
Tell her to pack up and leave town.
Why? What happened?
Just do it!
Oh Ma. Ma listen.
Get your stuff together and head
for Aunt Esther's.
Don't argue with me. Just go!
David, why did I just send
my mother to Atlanta?
David.
David talk to me.
Did you hear me tell you that the
signal hidden in the satellite feed,
is slowly recycling down to extinction?
Not really.
It's a countdown.
A countdown?
Wait. A countdown to what David?
It's like in chess.
First you strategically position your pieces,
then when the timing is right you...
strike.
See?
They are positioning themselves
all over the world
using this one signal
to synchronize their efforts.
In approximately six hours,
the signal is going to disappear
and the countdown is going to be over.
And then what?
Checkmate.
Oh my God.
Oh my God!
I have got to call my brother.
I would better call my housekeeper.
I got to call my lawyer.
Forget my lawyer.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the president of the United States.
Good afternoon.
My fellow Americans,
a historic and unprecedented
event has occurred.
The question of whether or not
we are alone in the universe
has been answered.
Although it's understandable,
that many of us feel a sense
of hesitation or even fear
we must attempt to reserve judgment...
He says, he is your husband.
Oh God.
What do you want?
You got to leave the White House.
This is hardly the time nor the place
to be having that same old discussion!
You don't understand.
You got to leave Washington.
Well in case you have not noticed
we are having a little crisis here.
They are communicating with a hidden signal.
They are going to attack.
You are just being paranoid!
It's not...
paranoia, the embedding is very subtle.
It's probably been overlooked.
Marty what are you doing?
Get out of town as soon as you can.
Please my staff and I,
Ok. Ok.
Will remain in the White House
as we attempt to establish communication.
If you feel compelled to leave these cities
please do so in an orderly fashion.
Hey! What's going on?
Excuse me.
Coming through.
The arrival of the alien visitors
has caused over 10000 fender-benders
in just a few seconds' time
but this, is just the beginning...
Come on now, you can't go.
You got to call them back.
I am not going to do this with you Jasmine.
I have got to report to El Toro.
But you said you was on leave for the 4th.
Yeah well they canceled it!
Look why are you acting like this?
Why?
That's why.
Look.
I really don't think they flew
90 billion light years
to come down here and start a fight
and get all rowdy.
Look why don't you just relax?
I am going to report to El Toro
and find out what's going on.
What are you doing in there man?
Nothing. I am just driving.
Look.
Here I got these for you.
Firecrackers.
Now you be careful.
Steve wait.
I want to tell you something.
What is it Jasmine?
You take care of yourself you hear?
Look...
Why don't you get some things packed,
and you and Dylan come stay
with me on the base.
And you will see that there is nothing
to be scared of.
Really?
You don't mind?
Well I mean...
We will have to let all
my other girlfriends know
that they can't come over you know
and got to postpone a little freaky-deaky.
There you go...
there he goes, thinking you all that.
But you are not as charming
as you think you are sir.
Yes I am.
Them big old Dumbo ears.
Look at you with them chicken legs.
Come on Dylan honey.
Look out!
What?
Hey!
The television said they started
the looting already heven't they?
Vultures.
You still have the Plymouth?
You want to borrow the car?
David you don't have a license.
You are driving.
Yeah I am driv...
I am driving?
Come on, come on.
I really want you out of Los Angeles.
You are staying there,
to keep people calm.
It's the right thing to do. I am not
going to let them criticize you for it.
I appreciate it your trying to help me.
Liar.
Stick to the truth
it's what you are good at.
Alright. I will tell you the truth.
I don't want you in any one of those cities.
I will leave as soon as
the interviews are done.
Alright.
There is a helicopter waiting.
They are gonna take you to Nellis.
And the munchkin?
She is going to meet you there.
Alright.
I love you.
Bye.
It's the White House for crying out loud!
You can't just drive up and ring a bell.
Can't this thing go any faster?
What you think
they don't know what you know?
They know. Believe me they know.
She works for the president.
They know everything.
They don't know this.
You are going to educate them?
Yeah so tell me something.
You are so smart.
How come you spend eight years at M.I.T
to become a cable repairman?
Dad!
No all I am saying is they got people
who handle these things David.
They want HBO they will call you.
Look at these, look at these people.
Look?
Vultures.
They take and then they go.
They are going, they are going
faster than we are.
Look at this, we are in the fast lane.
I can't go faster.
They are cutting me off here.
No one is cutting you off.
We are going to get a ticket.
They are getting in front of me.
I can't go any faster.
Alright. Alright.
I don't want to argue you.
Let's just get there,
as quickly as possible.
What's the rush?
You think we will get to Washington
it won't be there?
A local crop duster was arrested today
as he papered city hall
with leaflets from the air.
Everybody is leaving.
Can you give us some of your time?
Do you want to make a statement?
We have got to stop them!
I was kidnapped
by space aliens 10 years ago.
They did all kinds of experiments on me.
They ave been studying us for years,
finding out our weaknesses.
We have got to stop them!
They are gonna kill us all!
Some people attribute
his eccentric behavior
to post-traumatic stress syndrome
from his service as a pilot in Vietnam.
Others however have
a more unusual theory.
How would you describe Mr. Casse?
Private.
Keeps to himself.
Real quiet.
Quiet.
When they took him up in the spaceship
the aliens abused him...
sexually.
Mr. Casse is in the county lockup
this evening...
Pack up.
We are leaving.
Due to extenuating circumstances
he may be released later tonight.
Miguel what about Dad?
This could be our last night on Earth.
You don't want to die a virgin...
do you?
Come on we are going.
No. I am not going anywhere.
Miguel!
Stop it!
Thanks a lot partner.
You read my mind!
Stay here.
We got to get as far away
from these things as we can!
They let you out?
You damn right!
They got bigger fish to fry now
believe you me!
Come on boy!
We are leaving, without you.
We are going to live with Uncle Hector
in Tucson.
Hector!
Like hell you are.
I am still your father.
No you are not.
You are just the man
who married my mother.
You are nothing to me!
Well, what about Troy?
Troy?
Yeah.
For once in your life, why don't you
think about what's best for him?
So who has to beg for money to buy him
medicine when you screw up!
Who? Who?
You stop it right now!
I am not a baby anymore!
I don't want your stupid medicine
because I am so sick of medicine!
Do you know what this stuff costs?
Do you wanna get sick again?
Do you?
Once again the L.A.P.D.
Is asking Los Angelenos
not to fire their guns
at the visitor spacecraft.
You may inadvertently trigger
an interstellar war.
Think we can find something better
to do with our time gentlemen?
Where you been Stevie?
Man this is unbelievable.
This is like huge.
They-They ave recalled everybody.
Well looks like the mail is still working.
You got to do the honors for me man.
You are a wuss.
Yeah whatever shut up and read it.
It says...
Captain Steven Hiller
loser.
United States Marine Corps, blah, blah.
Come on. Come on. Come on. Come on.
We regret to inform you that...
despite your excellent record of service...
I am sorry man.
You know what you need to do?
You need to like kiss some serious booty
to get ahead in this world man.
That's what I am trying to tell you.
See I like,
the one-knee approach because...
it puts the booty like right...
in front of the lips, what's this?
That's nothing.
Hold on. Hold on man.
What is this?
Jasmine kind of has a thing for dolphins.
I don't know.
Stevie...
this is a wedding ring.
I thought you said you were going
to break the whole thing off.
Yeah.
Man you know I really like Jasmine.
You know that right?
Man you are never,
going to get to fly the Space Shuttle
if you marry a stripper.
It could only happen in California file
here is Wendy Walsh with a special report.
Below us we can see hundreds
of UFO fanatics
who have gathered
on rooftops here in downtown
Los Angeles to welcome
the new arrivals.
Oh God! I hope they bring back Elvis!
Do you think, I just came in
to get my check tonight,
and I got talked into working.
Oh I must have been tripping.
It's being called the party
event of the century
and everyone is invited
especially you know who.
This is so cool.
Girl please.
Oh, hey.
I made it before I came in tonight.
Check it out.
Now I know you are not thinking
about joining those idiots.
I am going over there as soon as I get off.
Do you wanna come?
Tiffany listen to me a second.
I have got a really bad feeling about this.
I don't want you to go.
Oh like the really bad feeling you got
when I went to Las Vegas?
Yeah. And I was right.
You didn't get the job
and you lost all your money gambling.
Yeah but...
I was not in L.A. for the earthquake.
Tiff I really don't want you to go up there.
Now promise me you won't.
Come on girl promise me!
No, no, no.
I promise.
Ok.
Look.
I am going.
I am out of town for a while.
Later.
Bye.
Hey there is my angel.
Come on.
Come on Boomer. Let's go.
Hey come on.
Talk to your boyfriend later.
Hey! What the hell's the kid doing here?
Get out of here!
You try finding a sitter today.
Hey! Hey where do you
think you are you going?
You leave, you are fired.
Nice working with you Mario.
Come on Boomer.
Everyone in the world is trying
to get out of Washington.
We are the only schmucks trying to get in.
What. What the hell is that?
Pops this is every phone book in America.
You think an important person
like Constance is going to be listed?
She always keeps her portable phone
listed for emergencies.
Sometimes it's her just first initial
sometimes it's her nickname
sometimes just her...
Oy my God!
Hey, hey, hey, hey! Slow down!
Where are they going?
Please stop!
Tell them! Tell them!
Slow down!
Off-ramp!
We made it! We made it!
Good, good.
Nice driving Pops.
Well...
So not listed?
No, no. I just have not found it yet.
I tried C. Spano Connie Spano.
Spunky Spano.
Spunky?
College nickname.
Cute.
You tried Levinson?
No she didn't take my name
when we were married.
Why would she...
What are you talking about?
Try it.
Ok. Here. Look.
So what do I know?
So...
You want to ring the bell or should I?
Oh perfect. She is using it.
Perfect. What's perfect?
It's busy.
Yeah. I can use her signal
to triangulate her exact position
in the White House.
You can do that?
Yeah.
All cable repairmen can Pops.
The visitors have arrived but the president
remains at the White House.
Question.
Are Mr. Whitmore's actions A ultra brave.
Or B foolhardy?
What?
Now don't hang up sweetie.
David.
How did you get this number?
Do me a favor.
Walk to the window.
And I am looking for what?
You will see.
Over here.
See us?
How does he do that?
Reporting live from Andrews Air Force Base
just outside Washington D.C...
Yes that's right Tom an amazing moment.
We are reporting from Andrews Air Force Base...
Now in light of our apparent inability
to communicate with the visitors
Pentagon officials have retrofit
this skylift helicopter
with a type of visual communications device.
Mr. President.
Gentlemen be seated.
This is not a military aircraft
but as you can see
Where are we now?
They are just commencing liftoff.
And refitted with these enormous
light panels,
that are attached to the hull
and onto the sides.
Echo One Welcome Wagon is in the air.
I repeat. Welcome Wagon is in the air.
Roger Welcome Wagon.
Echo One right beside you.
This is something I would never
believe in my lifetime
that I would be in the White House.
Look at this.
If I knew I was going to meet the president
I would have worn a tie.
Yeah I mean look at me.
I look like a schlemiel.
You look fine Pops.
Oy my God.
David I don't know how happy
he is going to be to see you.
Yeah that's right. I am telling you
we are wasting time.
Like he is not going to listen to me.
We should go?
Why would not he?
Why would not he listen?
Because last time I saw him we
we got into a fight.
You walked in the room
and punched him in the head.
You punched the president?
He was not the president then.
I punched him he fought back.
We wrestled around. It was a fight.
A fight that you started
because David thought that
I was having an affair.
With the president?
Which of course I was not...
Hey hey! You know either go get him
or we should head back to the car.
Alright. I will get him.
You wait here and don't touch anything.
You punched the president?
Mein Gott!
Nearing point of contact Echo One.
We are closing in.
Roger that. You are a go
to commence sequence when ready.
This I like.
Look at this!
You know what famous people
have been here?
Yes Dad.
Politicians actors...
Baseball players, singers...
And now me.
Imagine that!
Look a poor immigrant like me.
It's a dream!
David please!
The three choppers are
steadily approaching
what has been unanimously agreed
to be the front of these spaceships
a parabolic indentation 9 city blocks...
You are leaving now?
Hey see if they got those pens
that they give away.
Dad what?
You would still think I have
a choice of my company.
I don't have time for this.
Two minutes Tom.
Connie...
Mr. President. Mr. President.
Julius Levinson.
David is my son.
I told you he would not listen.
Νο you have to tell him now.
You are serious?
Tell him. David you have to tell him!
Hey Connie!
David tell him!
I know why we have satellite disruption.
Alright. Go ahead.
Ok.
Let's say that you want to coordinate with
spaceships on different sides of the Earth.
You could not send a direct signal, right?
You are talking about line of sight.
Yeah that's right, that's right.
The curve of the Earth prevents it.
If you need satellites
to relay that signal,
in order to reach each ship.
Well I found a signal
hidden inside...
our own satellite system.
Excuse me Mr. President.
They are starting.
They are using our own satellites against us...
and the clock is ticking.
Bringing it in to hover.
Welcome Wagon Echo One.
Approaching alien ship.
Initiating communications sequence,
Echo One.
Welcome Wagon has commenced.
General Grey coordinate
with the Atlantic Command.
Tell them to evacuate as many people
out of the cities as they can.
Yes sir.
Get those helicopters away from the ship.
Call them back immediately.
What the hell's going on?
We are leaving.
Kim my daughter.
There is something happening here.
They are responding.
Something is opening.
Something is happening.
It looks like there is some kind of activity here.
This may be some type of response
Echo One.
We see it too.
Can't identify it.
We are evacuating. I repeat.
We are evacuating the White House.
Load the rest of the staff
in the second helicopter.
Who should we pick?
Is my wife in the air?
She will be shortly.
Nice.
Very nice.
Ok. Buckle up.
Latch secure.
Look, we have our own phone.
Let's move out of here!
The president has ordered an evacuation.
We have to leave now.
And our prayers go out to the wives
and children of those brave pilots.
Indeed God help us all.
Come on.
The visitors responded with terrifying...
Authorities have called for a complete
evacuation of Los Angeles County.
People are advised to avoid the highways
wherever possible.
Oh yeah. Great.
Now he tells me.
This is the Los Angeles Police Department.
Please vacate the premises immediately
for your own safety.
Take me!
Can we move it along?
Dr. Katz's office.
Hello. Let me speak to...
Dr. Katz
Please.
I am sorry. He's not available.
Listen for $300 an hour you can put me
through to his house in the Hamptons!
This is the Los Angeles Police Department.
Please vacate the premises immediately
for your own safety.
Mrs. Whitmore.
You must leave now.
First lady secured.
We are on the move.
Look! They are opening up!
It's so pretty.
We got to get the hell out of here!
Go ahead pilot.
We are ready to take off right now.
Can you get a blanket for Patricia?
Here.
Over there?
Time is up.
Get down!
Oh crap.
Oh my God.
Come on Dylan.
We got to go.
Come on Boomer.
Boomer!
Reports are unclear as to the extent
of the devastation
but from all accounts
Los Angeles Washington
and New York have been left in ruins...
Good God!
I been saying it.
I been saying it for 10 damn years.
Ain't I been saying it Miguel?
I been saying it.
Dad I am sick. I don't feel good.
Pull it over man.
We are going to be alright Troy.
Leave me alone man I got it.
Miguel.
Look at all that.
We could have evacuated the cities hours ago.
That's the advantage of being a fighter pilot.
In the Gulf War we knew what we had to do.
It's just...
not simple anymore.
A lot of people died today.
How many didn't have to?
Any news on my wife yet?
The helicopter never made it to Nellis.
No radio contact.
Come on Dylan.
Stay close.
Here it is.
What happened Mommy?
I don't know baby.
You men will be the first wave
in our counterattack.
Our target is to the north,
centered above what remains
of down town Los Angeles.
You scared man?
No.
You?
Nope.
Hold me.
Hey, pay attention.
Something you want to add to this briefing
Captain Hiller?
No sir. I am just a little anxious to get up
there and whup E.T.'s ass that's all.
And you will get your chance.
You will all get your chance.
Good hunting.
Dismissed.
Let's kick the tires and light the fires
big daddy.
Let's bring it home.
Let's bring that bad boy home Captain.
You loose?
Yes sir.
You got your victory dance?
Well I got it right here, yeah.
Hey, don't get premature on me soldier.
We don't light up till the fat lady sings.
I am all ears brother.
You the man!
Alright gentlemen we are on.
General it's NORAD.
General Grey here.
Al?
All satellite microwave and ground
communications with the cities are down.
All systems go.
For intelligence we believe
we are looking at a total loss.
How about our boys?
Where are they?
ETA to target, four minutes.
I should not have left her.
Don't worry about it big man.
I am sure she got out of
here before it happened.
Or as the good reverend would say,
Why we are on this particular
mission we will never know.
But I do know, here today
that the Black Knights
will emerge victorious once again.
Amen man.
Amen Reverend.
Holy God.
Lock and load.
Roger that.
Los Angeles Attack Squadron has
Amraam missiles locked on target.
Washington and New York
squadrons reporting lock on.
Fire at will.
Knights we are red and free.
Knight 1 Fox 3.
Knight 3 Fox 3.
Knight 7 Fox 3.
Missiles have been fired.
Are they not getting through?
No sir. Not one.
Command Knight 1.
Switching to sidewinders.
Moving in.
Knight 3 Love 50.
Notch reference 1-2-0.
Knight 7.
1-2-0.
Knight 1.
Sweet luck.
Echo Fox 2.
Knight 7 Fox 2.
Come on. Come on.
They must have some kind of
protective shield over their hull.
Knights! Pull up! Pull up!
Knight 3 pull up!
Controls are showing complete
failure of the stats.
Pull up!
Blow through!
There is so many of them!
They got another one sir.
Oh no. You did not shoot
that green shit at me.
I have got you covered big daddy.
Damn. They got shields too.
Let's go Knights.
Move Knights move!
Jesus.
They got another one sir.
Two more just went down.
They are dropping like flies.
We are losing them.
Alright. Get them out of there.
Alright. Squadron leaders
retreat to fallback positions.
Abort mission. Abort mission right away.
Do you read me?
Do you copy?
Alright, I think we are going to make
a run for this one here.
Let's get low.
Let's get fast.
I got you big daddy.
Let's get them.
Watch the deck.
Do you read me your postion?
Squadron Leader do you read?
This isn't happening fast enough.
Abort!
Get them out of there!
What's with the monitor?
Where is the picture?
We have lost the satellite.
We got two R-6 Jimmy. Check them.
Roger.
Come on, come on, come on, come on.
Move, move, move!
He is on me like white on rice big daddy.
Alright Jimmy.
They ain't got nothing for us.
Let's push it.
We got to go! We got to go!
I can't shake them. I can't shake them.
Yes you can. Just the way
I showed you. Let's go!
Check me out.
Maybe I am going to try something.
Don't do nothing stupid over there.
You know me.
That's what I am talking about.
Jimmy! Jimmy! What are you doing?
You can't bank at that speed.
Jimmy he is closing on you!
Put your mask back on!
That's an order Marine!
I can't breathe!
Jimmy!
Jimmy! No!
That's affirmative.
We have incoming.
Let me have it son.
You got it.
Friendly?
Sergeant?
I don't think so.
Go! Go! Go! Go!
Come on and get me!
Come and get me!
What are you shooting at?
Where you at baby?
Come on! Come on!
You can't hit nothing!
Low bridge!
See if you can fly that thing undercover.
Hope you got an air bag.
Son of a bitch.
That's right!
Get off of me!
That's what you get!
Look at you!
Ship all banged up!
Who is the man?
Wait until I get another plane!
I am lining all your friends up,
right beside you!
Where you at?
Welcome to Earth.
Now that's what I call a close encounter.
Baby stay right here.
Stay right here with Boomer.
Keys.
Come on. Keys.
Yes!
Come on baby.
Come on.
Yes.
Rumor reports indicate that this battle
has repeated itself all over the world
with the exact same results.
You are just like your mother you know that?
She was stubborn too.
I had to twist her arm
to get her to take her medicine.
You are gonna be alright.
You are gonna be fine.
You see Troy?
You are feeling better already.
I could not find anything.
Everyone is packing up.
They are leaving.
They said there is a spaceship
heading this way.
We would better leave too then.
Penicillin. At least it will help you
keep his fever down.
Thank you.
It's really nice of you to help us.
I wish I could do more
but we are moving out.
I am going with you.
Well, I just mean that we are going too.
Cool.
Tell that punk to shut the door.
We are out of here.
He can sniff around somewhere else.
Bye.
It's Air Force One for crying out loud.
Still he gets sick.
I don't feel so good.
Look at me? Like a rock.
Could be bad weather could be
good weather. Doesn't matter.
We could go up, we could go down,
we could go back,
we could go forwards,
we could go side to side...
What did I say?
He still gets airsick?
Yeah.
Julius with all of this I...
I didn't get a chance to thank you two.
All he could think of was getting to you.
There is still love there I think.
Love was never a problem.
All you need is love.
John Lennon.
Smart man.
Shot in the back very sad.
We have moved as many of our forces
away from our bases as possible.
But we have already sustained heavy losses.
I spoke with the joint chiefs
when they arrived at NORAD.
They agree we must launch a counter
offensive with a full nuclear strike.
Over American soil?
You are saying at this point we should
sacrifice more innocent American civilians?
Is that right?
Sir, if we don't strike soon there may not
be much of an America left to defend!
Sir!
They have taken out NORAD!
What?
It's gone sir.
My God!
The vice president?
The joint chiefs?
Mr. President.
We must launch.
A delay now would be more costly than
when you waited to evacuate the cities.
No, no. You are not gonna
launch nuclear weapons!
You are gonna kill them and us at
the same time.
If we fire nukes...
then everybody else is going to fire them.
Sir may I remind you
You know what that means? Fallout!
You are a guest here.
You ever hear of nuclear winter?
David, you can't
It's the end of life as we know it.
Interfere with the conversation.
Do you hear what they are talking about?
I know I know.
Don't even think about it!
Just go.
I don't have to go.
You have to leave.
It can't be allowed!
Shut up! Captain get him out of here!
Hey, hey, don't tell him to shut up!
You'd all be dead now
if it was not for my David!
None of you did anything to prevent this!
There was nothing we could do.
We were totally unprepared for this.
Don't give me unprepared!
Come on Julius.
It was what? in the 1950s.
Whatever you had that spaceship.
Dad look Dad...
Yeah that thing that
you found in New Mexico!
Dad!
Where was that?
No, not the spaceship.
Roswell! Roswell New Mexico. Yeah!
No you had the spaceship
and you had the bodies!
They were locked up in a bunker.
Come on.
Where was that?
David?
I don't know.
Area 51! Right?
Area 51!
You knew then!
And you did nothing.
Sir.
Regardless of what you may
have read in the tabloids
there have never been any spacecraft
recovered by our government.
Take my word for it. There is no Area 51.
And there is no recovered spaceship.
Excuse me Mr. President.
That's not entirely accurate.
What? Which part?
Hold on everybody! Hold on!
Sorry.
The end hath come!
He speaketh His word
and the end hath come!
Hop on!
We are heading out to El Toro!
You cannot defy what hath come!
It is the end!
El Toro?
Can you give me a hand?
Yeah sure.
Oh God!
Ok, ok.
Let's get this off.
Here, let me help you.
She is hurt pretty badly.
You know,
this was supposed to be my weekend off.
But nooo...
you got me out here
dragging your heavy ass,
through the burning desert,
with your dreadlocks sticking
out the back of my parachute.
You got to come down here
with an attitude,
acting all big and bad.
And what the hell is that smell?
I could have been at a barbecue!
But I ain't mad.
It's alright.
Hey!
Do you need a lift soldier?
When I flew overhead
I saw a base not too far from here.
It ain't on the map.
Trust me it's there.
Ten hut!
Mr. President.
General.
Welcome to Area 51.
Please follow me.
We are now 24 floors beneath the surface
and...
here is our main research facility.
Let's see it.
I am sorry sir it's a clean room.
It's to keep it static free.
If we would all get to decontamination...
Open the door.
Yes sir.
My God!
Why the hell was not I told about this place?
Two words Mr. President.
Plausible deniability.
I don't understand.
Where does all this come from?
How do you get funding
for something like this?
You don't actually think
they spend $20000 on a hammer
$30000 on a toilet seat do you?
Mr. President, this is Dr. Okun.
He has been heading up the
research department on this...
project for the last 15 years.
How do you do?
Mr. President!
This...
What a pleasure!
As you can imagine they...
They don't let us out much.
I can understand that.
Well...
I guess you would like to see
the big Tamale?
Follow me.
She is a beaut ain't she?
As you can see from the repairs
we have been trying to put her back
together since the late 1960s.
Don't tell me you have had this for 40 years
and you don't know anything about them.
Oh hell no! No, no, no, no, no!
We know tons about them.
But, the neatest stuff...
The neatest stuff has only happened
in the last few days.
See we can't duplicate their type of power
so we have never been able to experiment.
But since these guys started showing up,
all the little...
gizmos inside turned on.
The last 24 hours have been really exciting!
Exciting?
People are dying out there.
I don't think exciting is the word
I would choose to describe it!
You guys are hoping to fly this thing?
You said you can repair their technology.
Can you tell us anything useful about them?
Oh yeah! Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well I mean...
They are not all that dissimilar from us.
Breathes oxygen,
comparable tolerances to heat, cold.
Probably why they are interested in our planet.
Hey!
You guys wanna see them?
This is...
This is the vault.
Or as...
some of us have come to call it...
the freak show.
When we found them
they were wearing...
some sort of...
bio-mechanical suits.
Once we got them off, we learned
a great deal about their anatomy.
Eyes, ears
no vocal cords.
We are assuming they communicate
with each other through some other means.
You are obviously not thinking about...
hand signals and body language.
It's some kind of extrasensory
perception telepathy.
So...
It's an organic life form.
Can they be killed?
Their bodies are just as frail as ours.
And these two died in the crash.
This one a few weeks later.
You just...
You have to get through their
technology which is...
I am sorry to say...
far more advanced.
David
you unlocked part of their technology.
You cracked the code.
Oh, no, no.
All I did was stumble onto their...
signal. I don't know how...
helpful I can be.
Why don't you show him
what you have discovered so far?
Figure out what they have not thought of yet.
We will see if you are as smart
as we all hope you are.
What code?
Captain Steven Hiller
United States Marine Corps.
I am sorry captain.
This is a restricted area.
I can't let you pass without clearance.
Ok.
Come here.
You wanna see my clearance?
Maybe I will just leave this here with you.
Let them pass.
Let them pass!
Get the hell out of the way!
Did you see that?
Come on down.
Look!
Watch your step.
Alright.
Yeah.
Well obviously this...
this cockpit
was designed to seat three.
Though, how they sat on them
I don't know.
Gently.
You see these gizmos flashing?
Yeah.
We have been working around the clock
trying to get a fix on all this crap.
Some stuff we figured out right away.
This we are pretty sure,
is the life support system for the cabin.
And this doohickey is connected to...
Well it...
was connected to the engine.
Here take that will you?
These configurations...
Well, to be honest we, we-we...
don't know what the hell this crap is.
But this...
is clearly what they use to...
guide and navigate their craft.
Neat?
Somebody could grab my laptop there?
Doc can I just, can I just have the...
computer inside.
What?
See these patterns here,
they are repeating sequentially,
just like their countdown signal.
They are using that frequency
for computer communications.
See?
That's how they are coordinating their ships.
You know...
You are really starting
to make us look bad.
They got one!
They got one alive!
Jesus!
Look.
You will be ok by yourself Dave?
Fine by it.
Yeah.
Don't touch anything.
Everybody is always telling me
not to touch anything.
Here, here.
It's all wet.
Right here.
We got him in the back of the pickup.
General sir. Captain Steven Hiller
United States Marine Corps.
Guess who is coming to dinner!
I need a doctor.
I need a doctor!
Oh boy!
How long has he been unconscious?
About three hours.
Let's get him in containment stat!
My son, he is very sick.
He needs immediate attention!
He is drying out.
I want him sprayed down with saline.
He has a problem with his adrenal cortex.
Please!
If you don't do something about it
right now my son will die!
Ok just help him!
Ok.
O'Haver, Miller you come with us.
You, take us to him, ok?
Let's go.
Alright! Move it, move it, move it!
As the former head of the CIA,
you knew about this place.
When were you planning
on informing the rest of us?
It had been deemed classified.
You should have told us about
this when they first arrived!
You should have warned us
before we launched a counterattack
that cost the lives of hundreds
of American pilots!
There was no way that we could have known
that our fighters would have been
that ineffective against their attackers.
Mr. President.
The little bit of information we have comes
directly into this room Mr. President.
Atlanta, Chicago and Philadelphia.
Destroyed.
We learned that NATO and Western Allied
installations...
were the first to be taken out.
Then we were hit.
They knew exactly where and how to hit us.
And our forces?
We are down to 15%.
If you calculate the time it takes
to destroy a city and move on
we are looking at the worldwide
destruction...
of every major city...
in the next...
36 hours.
We are being exterminated.
Mr. President.
This is Captain Steven Hiller.
Captain.
Mr. President.
Well done!
Where is it now?
We have it isolated down
in the containment lab sir.
I would like to go see it.
General,
I am really anxious
to get back to El Toro.
Has not anyone told you?
El Toro has been completely destroyed.
We were lucky.
Yeah!
Today was the first time I used the subway.
Thank God for the Metro Rail.
These should last us a while.
Don't move. I will get it for you.
Stay still.
He is your son?
He is my angel.
Was his father stationed here?
No he...
He was not his father.
But I was kind of hoping
he wanted the job though.
So what do you do for a living?
I am a dancer.
Ballet!
No.
Exotic.
Sorry.
Don't be.
I am not.
It's good money.
Besides...
My baby is worth it.
Dylan.
Come here.
I want you to meet the First Lady.
Hello.
Hi.
I didn't know that you would recognized me.
Well, I didn't want to say nothing.
I voted for the other guy.
Alright life support monitors recording.
So if we screw up, it's all on tape.
Ok, come on, come on, come on.
Let's get this bio mechanical suit off.
Put the spreader right here,
right along the ridge.
Microprobe thingamajig goes right here.
Pick there. Good.
Alright now spread it,
very, very gently.
Let me get in.
Gentle, gentle that's it.
Run this right, in...
Alright. Ok.
Let's proceed.
Now comes the...
the really icky part.
Oh boy!
This is one, smelly...
disgusting.
Oh look at it!
It doesn't look alive does it?
The arm is moving.
Doctor?
Doctor? Doctor?
Don't move! Don't move!
Oh my god!
Dr. Okun?
Release...
me.
Open the door. Get him out of there!
No wait.
Release me
now.
Now!
I know there is much
we can learn from each other
if we can negotiate a truce.
We can find a way to coexist.
Can there be a peace between us?
Peace?
No peace.
What is it you want us to do?
Die.
Die!
Sir!
Mr. President.
Is that glass bulletproof?
No sir.
Are you alright?
I saw...
his thoughts.
I saw what they are planning to do.
They are like locusts.
They are moving from planet to planet.
Their whole civilization.
After they ave consumed every
natural resource they move on.
And we are next.
Nuke them.
Let's nuke the bastards.
Just my luck. No ice.
I take it you have heard?
Hey toast.
To the end of the world.
He didn't come to this decision lightly.
He didn't have any other choice.
Well, you still believe in him.
Yeah.
Well he is a good man.
He would better be.
You left me for him or...
you know, for your career.
You know it was not just my...
career.
It was the biggest opportunity of my life.
I wanted my life to make a difference.
I wanted my life to mean something.
Yeah. And...
I was not...
ambitious...
David!
Enough for you?
David you could have done
anything that you wanted.
Research development...
Oh honey,
I was happy where I was.
Have not you ever wanted to be
part of something special?
I was part of something special.
Well if it makes any difference
I never stopped loving you.
But that was not enough was it?
Let's pick it up man. We have got
a tight schedule. Now let's go!
Let's pick it up man.
We are on a tight schedule. Let's go!
Let's go man!
Pick it up!
What the hell are you doing?
Get out of there!
Look I got something I got to handle.
I am just borrowing it.
No you are not sir.
Do you really wanna shoot me?
Just tell them I hit you.
Command this is Retal Op.
Squadron is in the air.
We are on station
and awaiting instructions.
Roger. Break formation.
Head to targets.
Sir...
They are breaking formation.
Mr. President we are
initiating sequence code.
Alpha. Zulu. Six. Eight. Niner.
Which city will be reached first?
Houston Texas.
ETA six minutes and counting down.
Houston.
The major cities have been deserted.
Civilian casualties should
be down to a minimum.
Command this is Neighborhood Watch.
We are in position.
Tracking monitors are locked on.
We are going to visual recon.
Roger that TC.
We have confirmation.
Launch code confirmed.
Alpha. Zulu. Six. Eight. Niner. Standing by.
Laser targeting.
Locked on.
We are locked on sir.
Do you wish to deploy?
Mr. President if you wish to deploy
the time is now.
Mr. President?
Deploy.
That's a go. Alpha. Zulu. Six. Eight. Niner.
That's correct. Deploy.
Here we go.
Bird is away.
We have visual confirmation of the missile.
It's on target.
Approaching.
May our children forgive us.
Five seconds to impact.
Three.
Two.
One.
Oh yeah! It's a hit!
Get down! Get down!
Can we confirm that
the target was destroyed?
Get the tank commander on line. I want
confirmation that the target was destroyed.
Yes sir!
Red Arrow Alpha 9723. Can you read?
Repeat Commander.
You are breaking up.
We have lost visual.
Roger that.
We are looking for confirmation.
We got the bastards.
Yeah!
Good job everyone! Congratulations!
Commander do you have visual?
I repeat we need visual confirmation.
Has the target been destroyed?
Negative.
Target remains.
I repeat,
target remains.
Call the other planes back.
Other bombers might have more luck.
We should not just give up on this!
I said call them back!
Abort.
Abort mission.
Issue the abort codes right away.
This is an abort, full abort.
Do you read?
Abort mission right away.
Jasmine!
You are late!
You know I like to make an entrance.
Where are we going?
Through there sir.
Mr. President your wife is resting
comfortably for the moment.
Perhaps if we had gotten to her earlier...
Hey, hey, there she is! Go on!
She doesn't look too good.
Your wife is bleeding internally Mr. President.
Perhaps if we had got her earlier...
Wait a minute. What are you saying?
We can't stop the bleeding.
If we had...
There is nothing we can do for her.
We were worried.
We didn't know where you were.
You have gotten bigger I think.
I did?
You just keep growing and growing.
I can't...
Hey.
Can you...
wait outside for a little bit
so mom can get a rest?
Hey come on Munchkin.
I am so sorry that I didn't come home
when you asked me to.
It's ok.
The doctors...
think that you are...
gonna be just fine.
Liar.
Is Mommy sleeping now?
Yeah.
Mommy is sleeping.
Hey.
David!
What the hell are you doing?
I am making a mess!
Yeah. This I can see.
We got to burn the rainforest
with toxic waste
pollute the air and rip up the ozone layer!
Because maybe if we screw
this planet up enough.
They won't want it anymore.
Wait, wait, wait. David. David!
Don't do this to yourself.
Listen to me.
I am listening.
Everyone loses faith
at some point in their life.
David. Even myself.
I have not spoken to God
since your mother died.
You see sometimes...
we have to remember what we still have.
Like what?
Well...
you still have your health.
Come on. David. David. you need your rest.
Come on!
Get off this freezing concrete floor
before you catch a cold. Come on.
What did you just say?
You mean about faith?
Well,
you see a man can live his life...
No, no, no.
No, the other part.
What? What?
I don't want you to catch cold.
What is that?
What's the matter with you?
Genius.
Genius?
My dad.
A total genius.
Jerry?
Wake up.
We got work to do.
Get everybody down here, right away.
What?
Look at that!
Does that thing really fly in outer space?
It most certainly does.
Sure doesn't look like it.
Hey, they are here.
Alright Connie what's this all about?
I have no idea.
Get everybody off.
Right everybody. Clear the platform.
Come on. Come on.
Major Mitchell...
Do you have a pistol?
What?
You got a gun?
Sergeant your sidearm.
See that...
Coke can on top of the alien craft?
Think you can shoot that thing off?
Do it. Shoot it.
Sir?
Go ahead.
What the hell are you doing?
I am sorry. My fault.
My-My fault.
That Coke can...
was protected by the craft's shield.
We can't penetrate their defenses.
We know that already.
What's your point?
Right. My point is
if we can't beat their defenses
then we got to get around them.
Major one more time...
Any time.
How did you do that?
I gave it a cold.
I gave it a virus.
A computer virus.
Are you telling us you can send out a signal
that will disable all their shields?
That's right. Just like they
used our satellites against us.
We can use their own signal...
against them.
If we plant a virus,
into that mother ship
it's gonna then filter down into
all the corresponding ships below.
I am sorry. I don't understand.
Just how exactly do we infect the
mother ship with this virus?
We are... We are gonna...
have to...
fly their alien craft out of our
atmosphere and dock with it.
We can enter here...
as shown in these satellite photos.
We then upload the virus.
We then set off some kind of explosion,
which will disable it.
And that will disorient
the smaller ships below.
And that could buy you
I think at least some time,
to...
to take them...
take them...
down, take them down.
Do your...
Do your stuff.
This is ridiculous!
How long would their shields be down?
I don't know. A matter of minutes.
You want us to coordinate
a massive worldwide counterstrike
with a window of only a few minutes?
With shields down
that might be possible.
Please!
We don't have the manpower or the resources
to launch that kind of a campaign!
Not to mention that this whole
cockamamie plan
is dependent on a machine that no one
in this world is qualified to operate.
I would not say that sir.
I have seen these things in action.
And I am well aware of their
maneuvering capabilities.
With your permission general
I would like the opportunity to try.
That thing is a wreck!
It crash-landed back in the '50s!
We don't even know if it's capable of flying!
Jim...
remove the clamps.
Any questions?
Let's do it.
Alright you heard the president
let's get this thing preped and ready to fly!
Good luck pilot.
Thank you Mr. President.
A virus!
Your idea.
That's right.
Do you really think you can fly that thing?
Do you really think you can do
all that bullshit you just said?
I understand, you are upset
over the death of your wife.
But that's no excuse for making
another fatal mistake.
No! The only mistake I ever made
was to appoint a sniveling little weasel
like you as Secretary of Defense.
I don't think you understand!
However!
That is one mistake I am thankful
to say that...
I don't have to live with.
Mr. President please!
Mr. Nimziki...
You are fired.
Let's organize every plane we can find
and get us some goddamn pilots to fly them.
Yes sir.
He can't do that.
Well he just...
did.
Command has attempted to compile
a list of casualties and losses
but information is sketchy at best.
Well we know we have lost
the Belgian contingent in the Sina.
There is a strong possibility there may be more
reinforcements hiding in the Golan Straits.
What the hell is he saying?
It seems they are getting a signal.
Old Morse code.
It's from the Americans!
They want to organize a counter offensive!
It's about bloody time!
What do they plan to do?
We have confirmed reports of...
combat ready divisions in Europe,
the Middle East and Asia.
That's impressive.
Considering it's all being done with...
Morse code.
The armed forces here?
We have sufficient aircraft
for the battle plan but...
But what?
Pilots are...
coming up short.
Well then find them.
Ham radio operators
from New York to Japan
trade rumors of military forces in hiding
unwilling to reveal themselves,
for fear of annihilation.
We are planning at this time
is to launch a counter offensive.
However with our depleted manpower
we are asking that anyone with any
flight experience come forward.
Military training is preferable
but anyone who can fly a plane
would be useful.
I can fly.
I am a pilot.
Alright guys listen up!
Alright pay close attention.
These F-18s are very different
than the jets you piloted before.
It's kind of strong.
You have to forgive the expression
but you are about to get a crash
course in modern avionics.
Keep it coming. Keep it keep it.
Ok you got it!
Alright listen up. Before we can
begin we are gonna have to get a little
background information
on your flight experience.
Let's start with you.
Who me?
Well I am...
Russell Casse sir.
And after Vietnam,
I got into...
crop dusting.
And...
been doing that ever since.
On a personal note sir
I would just like to add that...
ever since I was kidnapped
by aliens 10 years ago
I have been dying for some payback.
And I...
just want you to know that...
I won't let you down.
You have one tactical nuclear missile
we are loading into this launcher
we are installing under the right wing.
This is the firing mechanism.
It will be attached to the ship's main console.
Just like the Amraam launch pad on a Stealth.
Except the nuke will not detonate at impact.
You will have 30 seconds
to get your asses out of there.
Good luck gentlemen.
30 seconds.
Tell me, tell me.
Well it's the strongest radio transmitter
we could get.
It will tell us when you have
uploaded the virus.
30 seconds.
Don't you think that's cutting
it a little too close?
We are gonna be well on our way
back home before we shoot that thing off.
Why you? David!
I don't...
I don't understand...
why you can't show someone else
how to plant the virus.
Someone who is trained.
No.
No, something may go wrong.
I may have to...
think quickly adjust the signal.
Who knows? Hey.
You know how like I am always trying to...
save the planet?
Here is my chance.
Now he gets ambitious.
It's too tight.
Well I had to borrow it. Let me see.
Ok. Alright. I guess that's good enough.
So.
How do I look?
Oh thank you. You are a lot of help.
You are late!
Well you know me.
I know. You like to make a big entrance.
Listen.
Before we do this
I just wanna say I am sorry.
Sorry for what babe?
I should have done this a long time ago.
Do you have the ring?
Yes sir.
Here, make yourself useful.
Witnesses?
We got hung up.
Well let's get this show on the road.
Dearly beloved,
we are gathered here in the sight of God
and in the presence of these witnesses
to join this man
and this woman in holy matrimony.
Any person who can show good cause
why these two should not wed
please speak now
or forever hold your peace.
Steve,
will you take this woman
to be your wedded wife
to live together with her
in the holy state of matrimony?
Will you love her...
comfort her
honor and keep her in
sickness and in health,
and forsaking all others
keep yourself only for her,
as long as you both shall live?
I will.
Good morning.
They are a little young.
That they are.
They look a little nervous.
I need all flight crews to report
to their designated areas immediately.
Major,
can I borrow that?
Sir.
Good morning.
In less than an hour...
aircraft from here will join
others from around the world.
And you will be launching the largest
aerial battle in the history of mankind.
Mankind that...
word should have new meaning
for all of us today.
We can't be consumed
by our petty differences any more.
We will be united in our common interest.
Perhaps it's fate that
today is the 4th of July.
And you will once again
be fighting for our freedom.
Not from tyranny
oppression or persecution.
But from annihilation.
We are fighting for our right to live.
To exist.
And should we win the day
the 4th of July will no longer
be known as an American holiday,
but as the day when the world
declared in one voice.
We will not go quietly into the night!
We will not vanish without a fight!
We are going to live on!
We are going to survive!
Today,
we celebrate,
our Independence Day!
Let's go!
Mr. President.
Right this way sir.
I have got your gear over here.
Good luck!
I have got you a jumpsuit for you and the rest
of your gear is stored away in this duffel.
You have got your choice of helmets.
Mr. President I would sure like to know
what you are doing.
I am a combat pilot Will.
I belong in the air.
Ok sir. Let's get you airborne.
Right over here.
You know as soon as I get back
we are gonna light those fireworks right?
Here.
Take these.
Just in case.
Where is...
I am very proud of you.
Be careful ok?
It's time.
I love you.
Oh damn! Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait. Wait. We got to find some cigars.
I-I can't... I never...
Here, here!
Take these.
My last two.
You are a lifesaver.
Almost put a hex on the whole damn thing!
Missile launch.
Oh crap!
What do I hit? Which one?
I picked a hell of a day to quit drinking.
This is our victory dance.
Not until the fat lady sings.
Yes ok.
This is important.
Fat lady.
I got you.
Open launch tunnel.
Shaky?
Is it gonna do this the whole way?
Just make sure your seat backs and tray tables
are in their upright and lock position.
Yeah. Is it?
Let's rock 'n' roll.
Oops.
Oops?
What does that mean?
What do you mean...
No I-I got it. Look some...
jerk didn't put the diagram right.
I know what I...
mean when I say it.
What do you mean saying...
oops there?
What do you say we try that one again?
Yes, yes. Yes without the oops.
This is...
That a way!
I have got to get me one of these!
No, no, no! What was that?
What was that?
Don't do that!
Just trying to get a feel for
the old girl, that's all.
Oh, no, no, don't. Leave her alone. Really.
Look no hands.
Steve!
You are all secure sir.
Grey do you read me?
Roger Eagle One.
Your primary target has shifted course.
Which way they headed?
I think our secret is out.
They are headed straight for us.
ETA 26 minutes.
You still with me over there?
What the hell was I thinking?
I have been waiting for this my whole life.
Head straight for it.
What the hell?
Don't touch them. Don't, don't, don't!
I was counting on this.
They are bringing us in.
When the hell was you gonna tell me?
Oops.
We have got to work on our communication.
We have visual.
Do not engage until we have confirmed...
the package has been delivered.
Roger.
Major what happens if that thing gets here...
before the virus is planted?
Well ma'am this facility's
buried deep within a mountain.
It should provide us some protection.
Great.
What about the people outside?
Lieutenant Sell, we got incoming.
Oh my God!
Look at that!
There must be thousands of them.
Millions of them.
What the hell are they doing?
Looks like they are preparing an invasion.
Hey.
I don't like this.
This is stupid. They can see us!
Oh, no, no, no, no.
This thing comes fully loaded.
AM/FM radio, reclining bucket seats and...
power windows.
Come on baby.
We are in.
Do it.
Sir,
he is uploading the virus.
Eagle One, the package is being delivered.
Stand by to engage.
Roger.
Eagle One, check left.
Listen up!
We have an emergency situation.
We need everyone to grab
everything they can.
Only what you can carry.
We need to get you
inside immediately.
The virus is in.
All we can do now is...
pray.
Delivery complete.
Engage.
Delivery complete. It's a go!
It's a go!
Eagle One.
Fox three.
Gentlemen, this is it.
Come on, come on, come on.
Virus ineffective. Disengage.
Get your people out of there.
Disengage.
Rear flank follow suit.
Hold on Command.
I want another shot at it.
Sir I strongly recommend you disengage.
Eagle One.
Fox three.
Direct hit!
It's a hit. Squadron leaders
Fire at will! Fire at will! Fire at will!
We are going in.
Squadron leaders take flight.
Eagle Six at seven.
Eagle Five at three.
Eagle One. Fox two.
Eagle Twenty! Fox two!
Evasive maneuvers!
Squadron leaders! Evasive maneuvers!
Prepare to engage!
Alright Mr. President! Here we go!
Alright baby. I have got you!
Payback is a bitch ain't it?
Ok.
Job's done. Let's go home.
Gladly.
What's up?
It's stuck.
What?
It's not responding. It's stuck.
Try it again.
Come on, come on!
Steve. Steve!
Hey what the hell are you doing?
It's not me they are overriding the system.
Oh shit!
Hide.
Everybody hold someone is hand.
Hold hands.
Come on in.
I am not Jewish.
Nobody is perfect.
God!
Where are they?
This could be our last night on Earth.
I don't wanna die a virgin.
If we do,
we will both die virgins.
But at least we will be together.
Are you scared?
Me too.
Eagle Seven fox two.
Eagle Three fox two.
We are running out of missiles sir.
We are just not causing enough damage.
It's settling directly over us.
They are preparing
to fire their primary weapon.
Then let's take it out
before it takes us out.
Target at 12 o'clock.
My God they are everywhere!
Bandits on our tail! They are locked on!
I see them. I see them.
Alright squadron leaders
I want a weapons check.
You are out of time!
You have got to disable it now!
I am in range. Locking on.
I have got tone. Eagle One fox two!
That is a negative impact.
That is an NI. Negative impact.
I am out of missiles.
Eagle Two!
I am on it.
Oh Jesus!
Sir all missiles have been fired.
You are out of time!
Get your ass out of there!
We are not done yet!
Get as far away as you can!
Doesn't anyone have any missiles left?
Sorry I am late Mr. President!
Kind of got hung up back there!
Pilot you armed?
Armed and ready sir!
I am packing!
Who is that guy?
Put him on speaker.
Pilot identify yourself.
It's me!
Russell Casse sir.
I told you I would not let you down!
Just keep those guys off me
for a few more seconds will you?
Ok. Echo Niner Echo Seven.
Take flanking positions.
I want you to look after this guy ok?
Alright boys.
Let's give Mr. Casse some cover!
Gentlemen!
Let's plow the road!
We will draw them off
and it will be all yours!
Look out! Coming through!
I have got tone.
Eagle Twenty.
Fox two.
It's jammed.
It won't fire.
Damn it!
Do me a favor.
Tell my children...
I love them very much.
Alright you alien assholes!
In the words of my generation...
Up yours!
Dad! What's he doing?
Come on baby!
Come on baby, come on!
Good luck buddy.
Hello boys!
I am back!
He did it!
The son of a bitch, did it!
Alright!
What your father did was very brave.
You should be proud of him.
I am.
Now we know how
to take them out general.
Spread the word.
Get on the wire to every squadron
around the world.
Tell them how to bring
those sons of bitches down.
What do you think?
Checkmate.
Well it's funny. I always thought
that things like these would kill me.
Thank you.
It's been a pleasure.
Steve you too.
Only one thing left to do.
Ready?
Yes sir.
Hey, alright!
Look at us!
Take a look at the earthlings.
Goodbye!
You all take care alright?
Nothing but love for you!
Goodbye!
Nothing but love for you.
Do you think they have any clue
what's about to happen to them?
Not a chance in hell. Good night!
Peace!
We are loose.
Can you get us out of here in 30 seconds?
I ain't heard no fat lady!
Forget the fat lady.
You are obsessed with the fat lady.
Drive us out of here!
They are chasing us.
Oh really! You think?
Oh that was a hit. I took a hit.
We are not hit! We are not hit!
Stop side-seat driving!
Left. Left!
Tunnel tunnel!
Exit! Exit, left!
Where the hell do you think I am going?
Ok, ok. We ar-We are...
They are closing up on us.
Is that closing?
Shut up, shut up, shut up!
Must go, must go faster,
must go faster.
Go, go, go, go, go, go!
Elvis has left the building!
Thank you very much.
I love you. I love you man.
They are going down all over
the world Tom. We got them beat.
How about our two delivery boys?
Any word from them?
We lost contact with...
Captain Hiller and Levinson
nearly 20 minutes ago.
Hold it!
Hold on sir.
I have got something on radar.
Sorry sir.
Good job.
Thank you.
Well done captain.
Yes sir. Thank you sir.
David...
Not bad.
Thank you Mr. President.
Not too bad at all.
Oh so this is healthy?
I could get used to it.
Happy 4th of July Daddy.
Same to you Munchkin.
Didn't I promise you fireworks?
Yeah.
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections August 2022